准备直播 四 三…
And we're on in four, three,
二 一
two, one.
如果我说全美治安最差的城市
What if I told you that even the worst neighborhood in America
都能整顿到安全
could be made completely safe.
要是我说这能成真
And what if I told you that this could be accomplished
而且不危及任何一个警察的生命
without risking the life of one single law enforcement officer.
我怎么敢打包票？
How do I know this?
因为现在全世界每个国家都在改变
Because it's happening right now in every country in the world
只有美国除外
but this one.
我是派特诺维克 欢迎收看
I'm Pat Novak, and welcome to The Novak Element.
(诺维克关键时刻)
今晚的关键时刻环节
In tonight's State of the Union segment
我们请来孟罗将军
we'll be joined by General Curtis Monroe
在国防部战情室和我们现场连线
live from the War Room in the Pentagon.
孟罗将军 欢迎回来
General Monroe, welcome back.
很高兴见到你 派特
Good to see you, Pat.
感谢军方破天荒让我们参与行动
Thank you for this unprecedented access to your operations.
请告诉我们现在的情况
Could you walk us through what we're seeing here?
这是例行行动
Well, this is a routine operation.
我们发现随机巡逻
We found that random patrols
有助于当地居民对我们的信任
helped the local population to feel safer and to trust us.
不可思议
It's amazing.
将军 这些颜色代表什么？
And what are these colored dots that we're seeing here, General?
这是我们在当地的资产
These are our assets on the ground.
绿色是ED-209
In green, we got the ED-209s.
负责周边安全的大型机器人
They're the big boys. They secure the perimeter.
紫色是比较小的EM-208
Purple are the smaller E M-208s.
他们负责检查
They sweep and mop up.
派特 红色是你们的记者团队
And the red dots, Pat, that's your film crew.
很高兴看见美国制造的机器
It is great to see American machines
在海外促进和平与自由
helping to promote peace and freedom abroad.
好吧 这是例行行动
All right, you guys, this is a standard op, all right?
不会有冲突发生
There's no opposition expected.
这样机器会视你们的安全为优先
All our drones are gonna give top priority to your safety.
从来没有红色资产被杀
No red assets have ever been lost.
- 好吗？- 好
- Okay? - Okay.
你有比较放心吗？
Does that make you feel better?
但是 听着
But, listen,
只要戴着手环就不会有事
keep those bracelets on, you're completely safe.
好了？
Okay?
该上场了
Good. Enjoy the show.
我们走吧
All right. Let's go.
愿和平与你同在
May peace be upon you.
请走出房屋 举起双手
Please exit your homes with your arms raised
接受扫描检查
for a noninvasive scanning procedure.
没有人会受伤
No one will be harmed.
请走出房屋 举起双手
Please exit your homes with your arms raised
接受一种无害的扫描
for a noninvasive scanning procedure.
没有人会受伤
No one will be harmed.
史考特 拍这边
Scott, get me a shot of this.
感谢您的合作
Your cooperation is appreciated.
抱歉造成不便
We apologize for any inconvenience.
愿和平与你同在
May peace be upon you.
(扫描瞳孔 扫描指纹)
(拉蕾曼达尼 安全)
(无威胁)
不可思议
Incredible.
真是不可思议
Incredible!
不久前这任务是由美国士兵…
Not long ago, that would have been American men and women
冒着生命危险在进行
risking their lives to pacify these people.
将军 你的看法如何？
General, you care to comment on this?
好的 派特 越南 伊拉克 阿富汗的悲剧
Well, Pat, we had Vietnam, we had Iraq, we had Afghanistan.
决不会再发生
Never again.
这是军方无价的资产
From a military perspective, this has been invaluable.
我们不用再牺牲美国人的生命
We can accomplish our objectives without any loss to American lives
我想那里的好人也会衷心感谢
and I think the honest people over there really appreciate it.
这是当然的
And why wouldn't they?
这些人有生以来第一次 能看见他们的小孩
For the first time in their lives they get to watch their children grow up
在安全无虞的环境中长大
in an environment of safety and security.
纳维
Navid!
不要站在窗户边
Get away from the window!
妈 它们来了
Mom! They're here! They're coming!
快过来
Come here! Come here right now!
阿拉西
Arash!
纳维 保护你妈和妹妹
Navid! You stay with your mom and sisters!
他只是个孩子
But he's just a kid.
莎耶
Sayeh!
和你妈和妹妹待在家里
Stay here with your mom and the kids!
- 你在干什么？- 照我说的做
- What do you think you're doing? - You heard me!
阿拉西 拜托别这样
Arash, please don't go! Don't do this!
纳维 快过来
Navid! My dear! Come back here!
纳维
Navid!
把门关上
Shut the door!
我们不是要干掉它们
We're not here to kill any of them.
知道吗？
Got it?
重点是我们在电视上被杀
The goal is to die on television.
走吧
Let's go!
凯莉
Kelly!
你听得见吗？
Can you hear me out there?
很清楚 派特 记者现在在德黑兰
Loud and clear, Pat. I'm here in sunny Tehran
当地居民显然乐意接受例行扫描
where locals have clearly embraced these routine scans.
你可以看见这些居民都很合作
As you can see behind me, they're working in collaboration with the robots
显然维护居民的安全是首要任务
and obviously their safety is everyone's top priority.
我下令前不要动作
Don't make a move before I say...
我要确定他们有在拍
I wanna make sure they're recording.
好
Yes!
好的
Yes! Yes!
我们准备好了
We're ready.
你得告诉儿童
You'll notice children
街上那些儿童 这真是…
in the streets as well. This is everyday life
和平美好的一天
happening in perfect harmony.
太好了 这 来这
Oh, great. Here, come here.
不要动 不要动
Stay put, stay put, stay put.
别担心 机器人会处理
It's fine. Don't worry. My guy's got it.
纳维 窗户边很危险
Navid! It's dangerous here!
过来
Come away! Come...
你要去哪里？
Navid, where are you going?
看着我 纳维
Look at me! Navid! Navid!
你在找什么？
What are you looking for? Navid!
纳维 你在做什么？
Navid! Navid! What are you...
纳维 别去
Navid! Don't go! Navid!
我的天
Oh, my God!
放下武器
Drop your weapon.
(威胁 攻击)
凯莉？
Kelly?
凯莉 你还好吗？
Kelly! Are you all right? Kelly!
我们没事 派特
We're okay, Pat.
机器人刚击毙炸弹客
Our robots have just repelled some suicide bombers.
抱歉 凯莉
I'm sorry, Kelly,
基于安全理由国防部要切断讯号
but for security reasons the Pentagon's going to cut our feed to Tehran.
请多加小心
But, please, be careful.
好 我会持续待命
Yeah. I'll continue to stand by.
各位看见机器人在海外的重要性
Now you see how fundamental these robots are to our foreign policy.
所以我不禁要问
So then tell me.
为什么美国不能使用这些机器？
Why can't we use these machines here at home?
为什么美国这么怕机器？
Why is America so robophobic?
一边我们请到雷蒙赛勒斯
On the one hand, we have Raymond Sellars.
他是企业家和真正的爱国者
An entrepreneur and true American
他的产品刚救了我同事的命
whose product just saved my colleague's life.
另外一边请到的是
And on the other.
修伯崔佛斯
Hubert Dreyfus.
紧抓过去不肯前进的人
A man with both feet planted firmly in the past
他的法案禁止在美国使用机器人
whose bill prohibits the use of drones on US soil.
美国人支持崔佛斯法案
The American people support the Dreyfus Act
是因为他们没见识过这种科技
because they haven't experienced this technology
人们对不了解的事感到害怕
and they fear what they don't understand.
本节目支持赛勒斯先生
We at The Novak Element support Mr. Sellars' efforts
他努力想让我们的国家更安全
to make our country and our viewers safer.
毕竟
After all,
有什么比美国人的安全更重要？
what's more important than the safety of the American people?
《新机械战警》
(底特律警局总部)
- 墨菲 - 嗨
- Hey, Murphy. - Hey.
杰克还好吗？
How's Jack?
还不知道
We don't know yet.
- 墨菲 - 嗨
- Hey. - Murphy.
- 还好吗？- 还好
- How's it going? - Good.
他们在这里干嘛？
What the hell are they doing here?
六死 路易斯受伤
Six in the morgue. Lewis in the hospital.
你闯下大祸
This was the mother of all bad ideas.
我们追到安东尼范伦的线索
We got a lead on Antoine Vallon, we took it.
什么线索？
What lead?
不要在他们面前说
Not in front of them.
- 胡扯 - 是吗？
- This is bullshit. - Yeah?
你对我们有意见？墨菲
Yeah, you got something to say, Murphy?
范伦是我们的案子
Vallon's our case.
两年啥都没有？你们不是笨就是有鬼
Yeah, two years without no arrest, no nothing? You've gotta be dumb or dirty.
你有证据？还是看我们不顺眼？
You got something on us? Or is this personal?
这无关私人恩怨
No, it's nothing personal.
不过我是看你不顺眼
Although, I don't like you as a person.
好了 你们俩出去
Okay, you two, out.
没问题
No problem.
要不是你
Maybe if you hadn't gone off the reservation,
他现在还活跳跳
your partner would still be standing.
- 你说什么？- 够了
- What'd you say to me? - Hey, that's enough!
艾力克斯
Okay, Alex.
现在只有我们俩
It's just you and me now.
我和杰克去买赃物
So me and Jack, we've been doin' some street buys.
我们发现一些枪的线索
We get a line on some guns.
我们和一个小混混杰瑞碰面
We meet up with this low-level G called Jerry
他手里竟然有高级军火
who ends up havin' a piece he's not supposed to have.
你怎么有这种枪 杰瑞？
Where the hell you get a gun like that, Jerry?
我可以给你两大箱
I can get you two whole crates full, man.
两箱？
Two crates?
你这小咖哪来这么多枪？
No disrespect, J, but how a clown like you get so much product, man?
关你屁事？
What's it matter where it comes from?
当然有关 我们不要赃货
Why it matters, we don't want no dirty guns, Jerry.
这些枪杀过人吗？
These guns got bodies on 'em, Jerry?
这是干净的 对吧？
Yo, look, they're clean, all right?
你们到底买不买？
You gonna buy this shit or not?
你干嘛这么紧张？你有鬼？
Why you acting so nervous, man?
你在钓我们？
You fishin' on us, Jerry?
你在说什么？
What'd you say?
- 你觉得他有鬼？- 我觉得他在钓我们
- You think he fishin', D? - I think he's fishin' on us.
你们在说什么？
Yo, what the hell are they talkin' about, man?
你电话给我
Hey, let me see your phone.
给我看你的电话
Let me see your phone.
我才不要给你我的电话
I'm not showing you my phone, man!
你在录音？
You recordin' this?
你他妈的是条子
I think you're a goddamn cop!
你在胡说什么？
What the hell are you talkin' about, man?
我才不给你电话
I'm not showing you my phone!
把枪放下
Hey! Put your gun down!
你电话拿来
Put your phones on the table.
我们不是警察 我们替范伦工作
We're not cops, all right? We work for Antoine Vallon.
什么？
What?
闭嘴 你刚说什么？
Shut up! Shut up! What'd you say?
原来他替范伦工作
Ends up he works for Vallon.
在碰面前我们查了枪枝编号
Before the meet, we ran the serial numbers on the rifles.
这些枪应该在警局的证物室
The guns were supposed to be in our evidence room.
不是外头
Not out on the street.
证物单是空白的 没有签名
Intake papers blank. No signatures.
- 怎么样？- 都是空的
- What do you got? - Nothin'.
你觉得怎么会这样？
How do you think that happened?
墨菲 我们不该这么做
I'm telling you, Murphy, this is a mistake.
这些人杀人不眨眼
These guys'll shoot you just to see if they gun work.
我们需要支援
We need backup.
那样会有人给他通风报信
If we call for backup, word's gonna get around the station.
他会逃跑的
He's gonna disappear.
不会有事的
It's gonna be all right.
我们告诉范伦我们要买枪
So we told Vallon we were gun buyers,
他相信了
and he bought it.
为何要那么多枪？你们想造反？
What do you two need with that much product? You plotting a coup?
别担心 不是用来对付你们
Man, don't trip, we ain't gonna bust a single shot in your town.
我们跟芝加哥警局有帐要算
We got some problems back home with Chicago PD.
我听说你不喜欢警察
Yeah, I heard you don't like cops.
老大
Hey, boss.
什么事？
What do you got for me?
真的？
Really?
就在快成交时 有人通知他
We were just about to close the deal but someone tipped him off.
我必须接这通电话
Gentlemen, I gotta deal with this.
两分钟
Two minutes.
把两个都杀了
Make sure you kill 'em both!
两支手枪 一支自动步枪
I got two handguns, one automatic.
我们得出去 我来对付自动步枪
We gotta get out of here. I'm gonna take the automatic.
你确定？
You sure about this?
好了吗？
You ready?
走
Move.
路易斯
Lewis!
警员中枪 汉米顿街331号
Officer down! Officer down, 331 Hamilton.
艾力克斯墨菲警探请求医疗支援
This is Detective Alex Murphy in need of immediate medical assistance.
汉米顿街331号
331 Hamilton Road.
杰克
Jack.
杰克 听得见吗？
Jack, come on. Jack. Can you hear me?
杰克 撑着
Jack. Stay with me.
杰克
Jack.
艾力克斯 你不能擅自行动
Alex, you don't do something like this
你必须先来找我
unless you bring it to me first.
范伦的交游广阔
Vallon's connected.
我警告你 不要再自作主张
I'm warning you, don't make any more moves until I vet this.
有内贼偷枪给他…
If officers are supplying him with guns...
交给风纪委员会调查
That's up to IAD.
我会处理
I'll handle it.
(华盛顿特区)
赛勒斯先生 不管机器人多精良
I don't care how sophisticated these machines are, Mr. Sellars.
机器无法像人类一样有感觉
A machine does not know what it feels like to be human.
它不能了解人类生命的价值
It can't understand the value of human life.
我们怎能允许它取人性命？
Why should it be allowed to take one?
这种攸关生死的事
To legislate over life and death,
应该交给能分辨对错的人
we need people who understand right from wrong.
你的机器人有什么感觉？
What do your machines feel?
他们不会感到愤怒 不会有歧视
Well, they feel no anger. They feel no prejudice.
也不会疲倦 所以非常适合执法
They feel no fatigue, which makes them ideal for law enforcement.
让这些机器人到街上
Putting these machines on the streets
能拯救无数美国人的生命
will save countless American lives.
- 你在回避问题 - 我没有
- You're evading the question. - No, I'm not.
你有 你在回避问题
Yes, you're evading the question.
我问你机器有什么感觉？
I asked what do these machines feel?
要是它们杀了小孩
If one of them killed a child,
它有什么感觉？
what would it feel?
- 没感觉 - 这就是问题所在
- Nothing. - And that's the problem.
所以72%的美国人反对机器执法
That's why 72% of Americans will not stand for a robot pulling the trigger.
(底特律 欧姆尼总部)
全世界最大的市场我们不能碰
America is the world's most valuable market, and we can't touch it.
跨足美国市场每年能赚进六千亿
With a domestic expansion, we'd clear $600 billion per annum.
换句话说只要那法案存在的一天 我们就在失血
In other words, every second that law is in existence, we are hemorrhaging money.
你要我怎么做？
What do you want me to do?
我们捐钱给两党 但没人买帐
We've thrown cash at senators at both sides of the aisle. Nobody's budging.
他们不想惹恼选民
They don't want to vote against their constituents.
除非说服民众 否则没有胜算
So unless we sway public opinion, the battle's lost.
为了达成这个目的
Now, to that effect,
我的团队想出积极的行销策略
my team have come up with a pretty aggressive new campaign.
吸睛指数破表
Wow factor off-the-charts.
美国人要的是他们能爱上的产品
We need to give Americans a product they can love.
一个真正的英雄
A figure they can rally behind.
我研究过 这法案没有漏洞可钻
Sir, I have dissected this bill. There are no loopholes.
不能就这样把机器摆上街头
We can't put a machine on the streets.
别管机器了
Forget machines.
你们看到民调结果
You saw the polls.
美国人不要机器
Americans don't want a machine.
他们要的是能分辨善恶的产品
They want a product with a conscience.
他们要的是…
They want something that knows
像人类一样有感情的
what it feels like to be human.
我们要把人放进机器里
We're gonna put a man inside a machine.
(欧姆尼基金会复健病房)
你不是你的脚 手臂或手
You're not you because of your legs, your arms, your hands.
你的脑才是关键
You're you because of your brain.
你的脑处理资讯 让你成为你
It's your brain's capacity to process information that makes you who you are.
(丹尼诺顿博士 欧姆尼基金会)
放轻松 像平常一样就好
Relax, and just do what you've always done.
我没用这个弹过吉他
I've never played with these.
音乐不是来自手指 而是你的心
The music doesn't come from your fingers, Michael, it comes from your mind.
只要让音乐自然流露
All you have to do is let it out.
请
Please.
我的天
Oh, my God.
没关系 放轻松
No, it's okay. Easy.
他很激动 资讯传递受阻
His emotions are peaking. The readings are getting clouded.
好
It's okay.
放轻松 太激动会影响脑化学
Relax. If you get too emotional, it'll change the chemistry in your brain.
使系统故障
It'll throw the system out.
你做得很好 加油
You're doing great. Come on.
我需要情绪才能演奏
I need emotion to play.
阿兰奎斯协奏曲 第二乐章
Concierto de Aranjuez, second movement.
太动人了
Beautiful piece.
丹尼 我需要和你谈 谢谢
Dennett, when you have a moment. Thank you.
雷蒙 你早就答应过我
Now, we agreed on this a long time ago, Raymond.
不会要我发展武器应用
I wouldn't be asked to develop combat applications.
我的工作纯粹为了科学进展
My work here is driven by its own questions.
你的工作很了不起 但应用太少
And your work is brilliant. But your ideas are being underutilized.
我想到一个办法
Look, I think I found a way
不但能获利支持你的研究
to put real revenue stream behind your research
也能拯救上千万人的性命
and save thousands of lives in the process.
你们没尽责 差点害我被抓
You're not keeping up your end, leaving me exposed like that.
墨菲警探只是太冲动
Detective Murphy's just a little impulsive.
那就收买他
So put him on the payroll.
有什么问题？
Why are we talkin' about this?
他不会收 现在他搭档又受伤
It won't work. And now that his partner got hit,
他绝对不会放任不管
he's never gonna let it go.
- 这是什么？- 路易斯住的医院
- What is that? - Lewis' hospital.
艾力克斯下午会去 也许你想送花
Alex is dropping by this afternoon, in case you want to send flowers.
是啊
Yeah.
杀警察要躲一辈子
I kill a cop, lookin' over my shoulder the rest of my life.
对生意不好
That's not good for business.
你觉得这案子会由谁负责？
Who do you think's gonna be investigating you?
我要全力调查雷克和丹尼尔
I'm gonna go hard after Lake and Daniels.
我要在一个月内逮捕他们
I'm gonna have 'em in bracelets within a month, man.
(派代纪念医院)
范伦 我到了
Hey, Vallon, I'm walking up right now.
摄影机关了吗？
Cameras off?
安全
Clear.
你是对的 我们应该等后援
You were right. We should've had backup.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你不是真的在睡吧？
You're not really sleeping, are ya?
混蛋
Asshole.
纽约市警汤玛士莱恩 下身瘫痪
Sergeant Thomas Ryan, NYPD. Paralyzed from the waist down.
意外发生后他有点发福
He has let himself go a little since the accident.
下一个
Pass.
好 有道理
Yeah. Yeah, fair enough.
丹佛市警察 艾佛米勒
Officer Alfred Miller, Denver.
严重小脑…
"Severe Cerebellar..."
小脑运动失调
Cerebellar ataxia.
你果然是医生
That's why you're the doctor, Doctor.
他很受都市居民欢迎
He scored through the roof with our urban demos.
这个纳入考虑 我喜欢他
Let's keep this one in mind. I like this guy.
很好 我把最好的留到最后
Very good, sir. I saved the best for last.
杰克富利曼警官 完美男性典范
I give you Sergeant Jack Freeman, masculinity incarnate.
五年匹兹堡特勤组长 现在坐轮椅
Led Pittsburgh SWAT for five years, now confined to a wheelchair.
我觉得他很有吸引力
I think I can see the appeal.
不行
No.
什么？为什么？
What? Why?
他的精神评量太不稳定
Well, check the psych evaluation. He's far too unstable.
他意思是他容易生气
He's trying to say that he has a temper.
你们知道他会经历什么吗？
Have you any idea what we'd be putting him through?
我们需要心理平衡的人才行
The psychological strain requires someone emotionally balanced.
我们必须保持客观
We have to be scientific.
我们不是要卖饮料 对吗？
I mean, we're not selling a soft drink here, are we?
他是对的 继续找
He's right. Okay. Keep looking.
大卫 没吃完饭不能看比赛
David, what did I say? Not until you're finished.
- 我回来了 - 爸
- Hey, guys. - Hi, Dad.
- 嗨 - 小猴子
- Hey. - Hey, little monkey.
比数怎么样？
How's the game, buddy?
戴蒙被停赛 不过对方少两人
Damon got ejected, but we got a two-man advantage.
是吗？太棒了
Oh, yeah? That's fantastic.
大卫 你该上楼睡觉了
Hey, D, why don't you head upstairs and start getting ready for bed.
可是爸才刚回来
But he just got home.
等等就上去
I'll be up in a second.
帮你盖被子 好吗？
Tuck you in, okay? All right?
- 给妈咪亲一个 - 晚安宝贝
- Now give your mom a kiss. - Good night, baby.
晚了一步
Too slow, boy.
你动作太慢
You're just too slow.
杰克还好吗？
How's Jack holding up?
还要一星期才能下床
They said a week till he's back on his feet.
都是我不好
It's my fault.
不然他不会受伤
We shouldn't even have been there.
给你
Here.
可恶 我以为修好了
Oh, shit, I thought I fixed that.
等下就停了
It'll stop.
会吵醒大卫
It's gonna wake up David.
他全身80%的面积四度灼伤
He suffered 4th degree burns over 80% of his body.
腰椎已经切除
Lower spine has been severed.
要是他能活下来
If he survives,
腰部以下会瘫痪 需要坐轮椅
he'll be paralyzed from the waist down and confined to a wheelchair.
墨菲太太
Mrs. Murphy,
我们不一定要讨论这些
we don't have to do this.
我必须知道所有细节才能做决定
I need to know everything before I make a decision.
请继续
Please continue.
前庭耳蜗神经 视神经严重受损
Vestibulocochlear, optical nerves have been critically damaged.
他一只眼睛会瞎掉
He'll be blind in one eye.
很可能全聋
Most likely deaf.
坦白说诺顿博士是这方面的权威
Frankly, Dr. Norton and the Omni Foundation are the leaders in this field.
我认为这是你先生唯一的机会
In my opinion, this is the only chance your husband has.
我会认真考虑他们的提议
I'd seriously consider their offer.
很抱歉 医生
I'm sorry, Doctor.
我需要时间思考
I need time to think.
墨菲女士 恐怕你时间不多
I'm afraid, Mrs. Murphy, time is one thing you don't have.
你说你能救他 这是什么意思？
You say you can save him, but what does that mean?
他以后的生活会变怎么样？
What kind of life will he have?
(三个月后)
- 谢谢 - 谢啦 兄弟
- Thanks. - Thanks, buddy.
她一定又要我跳舞
You know she's gonna make me dance again.
我得亲眼看看
Now that I've gotta see.
你不会想看
You don't want to see that.
她来了
Here she comes now.
帮我拿一下
Hold on to that.
去吧
Get out there, partner.
你每次都这样
Every time.
加油
Get her, boy.
对象还在作梦
Subject is still dreaming.
他在撷取记忆
He's retrieving memories,
试图合理化刺激封包37
trying to make sense of sensorial stimulation package 37.
太好了 金
Perfect, Kim.
连接脊椎
Let's reconnect the spine.
该叫醒他了
Time to wake him up.
抱歉？
Excuse me?
你们在干嘛？
What are you doing here?
宝贝 你去哪里？
Baby, where you going?
路易斯
Lewis.
对象重新获得认知功能
Subject regaining cognitive functions.
怎么回事？
What's happening?
我在哪里？
Where am I?
你经历一场爆炸 艾力克斯 你现在在医院
You were in an explosion, Alex. You're in a hospital.
克莱拉呢？我老婆 她在哪里？
Where's Clara? My wife. Where's my wife?
我要你冷静下来 听我说 艾力克斯
I want you to calm down, Alex. Listen to me.
你没事 你家人也都没事
You're okay. And your family's fine. Both your wife and your son.
你是谁？
Who the hell are you?
我是丹尼诺顿博士 负责治疗你
I'm Dr. Dennett Norton. I'm treating you.
心跳加速
Heart rate rising.
我不能动
I can't move.
我不能动 这是什么鬼东西？
I can't move. What the hell is all that?
视力输入不稳
Visual input unstable.
我要你放轻松 艾力克斯
I want you to relax, Alex.
对象肾上腺素过高
Subject's dumping too much epinephrine.
- 要清除吗？- 还不要
- Should we purge it? - Not yet.
释放脊椎
Unlock vertebrae.
继续
Go ahead, Kim.
释放上肢 下肢
Unlock upper, lower extremities.
这是什么装备？
What kind of suit is this?
这不是装备 艾力克斯
It's not a suit, Alex.
这是你
It's you.
这是唯一的选择
This was the only option.
我们在这里是为了让你重生
We're here, all of us, to make you whole again.
释放全身
Full body unlock.
现在走路 艾力克斯
I want you to walk now, Alex.
你做得到
You can do that.
感觉好真实
This seems so real.
艾力克斯 你必须了解发生什么事
Alex, it's very important you understand what is happening.
这是真的
This is real.
不是梦 药物或麻醉
It's not a dream, it's not drugs or anesthetics.
我是在作梦 我感觉得到
I know I'm dreaming 'cause I can feel all of this.
艾力克斯 截肢的人感觉得到截掉的肢体
Alex, amputees can often feel their missing appendages.
这叫幻肢
It's called phantom limb sensation.
什么"截肢的人"？
What do you mean "amputees"?
- 你对我做了什么？- 你放轻松
- What the hell did you do to me? - You need to relax.
把这衣服拿掉
Take this off me now.
我要脱掉这东西 你做了什么？
I need to get out of this thing. What did you do to me?
你对我做了什么？
What have you done to me?
艾力克斯？嘿
Alex? Hey!
关掉他
Shut him down.
不 让他跑
No! Let him run! Let him run!
(无身分资料 资料库离线)
我在哪里？
Where am I?
艾力克斯 拜托
Alex, please.
停下来
Stop.
艾力克斯 你必须停下来
Alex, you have to stop.
拜托
Please.
艾力克斯
Alex.
请停下
Please stop.
站在那里 我们会去接你
Stay where you are and we'll come and pick you up.
(欧姆尼财产 不得攻击)
(高度18尺 距离23.02尺)
好吧 金
Okay, Kim.
关掉他
Shut him down.
艾力克斯
Alex,
你逃不掉的
you can't run from this.
你必须了解现实状况
You have to understand the reality of the situation.
给我看
Show me.
金
Kim.
噢
Oh!
不
No.
天哪
Holy Christ.
老天
我什么都不剩
Holy Christ, there's nothing left.
你的身体不在 但你人还在
Your body may have gone, but you're still here.
那甚至不是我的脑
That's not even my brain.
我们必须修复受损区域
We had to repair the damaged areas.
但没有干扰你的情绪或智力
But we didn't interfere with your emotion or your intellect.
你了解吗？艾力克斯
Do you understand me, Alex?
你还是有主控权
You're in control.
- 我有主控权？- 对
- I'm in control? - Yes.
好
Okay.
要是我有主控权
If I'm in control,
那我想死
then I wanna die.
把所有插头拔掉 结束这场噩梦
Just unplug whatever it is keepin' me alive and end this nightmare.
要是我这么做
Now, say I did that.
虽然不可能 但假使我做了
Which as a doctor would almost be impossible for me, but say I did.
我怎么跟你老婆交代？
What do I say to your wife?
她要怎么跟你儿子说？
What does she say to your son?
就说没有用 你尽力了
That it didn't work. That you tried.
说出了问题
Somethin' went wrong.
能做的都做了
You did everything you could,
但我还是死了
but I died.
他们承受 经历所有痛苦跟期待
So after all they've been through, all the pain, all their hope restored,
你要剥夺他们的希望？
we would just rip that away?
你老婆爱你 艾力克斯
Your wife loves you, Alex.
她亲手签同意书
She signed the consent forms herself.
否则 你不能动手术
Otherwise, you couldn't have undergone the procedure.
她爱你 她给你第二个机会
She loves you and she gave you a second chance.
我要你接受这个机会
I need you to take it.
我不要再看见我自己
I don't wanna see myself like this again.
永远不要
Ever.
我家人也一样
And the same goes for my family.
把我装回去
Just put me back in.
拉近
Zoom in.
停
Stop.
拉近
Zoom in.
停
Stop.
接受连线
Accept the connection.
我好高兴终于看见你
It's so good to finally see you.
我也很高兴
I was gonna say the same thing.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我知道我看起来很怪
I know how I must look to you.
你看起来很美
I think you look beautiful.
宝贝 他们对你好吗？
Are they treating you okay, baby?
目前还好 诺顿博士的人还不错
So far. Dr. Norton, he seems like a nice guy.
大卫知道你打给我吗？
Does David know you're calling?
他很想你
He misses you.
- 我可以去叫他 - 不
- I can go get him. - No.
我不想让他看见我这样
I don't want him to see me like this.
还不想
Not yet.
好
Sure.
我们会撑过去的 宝贝
We're gonna get through this, baby.
我们会像以前一样
We're gonna make it like it was.
你什么时候能回家？
When are you comin' home?
他们还要做测试
Well, they've still got some tests.
不过他们说很顺利
But they're sayin' it's goin' really well.
一有机会我就回去
The minute they let me.
我要挂了
I gotta go.
我爱你
I love you.
中断连线
End the connection.
开始血液净化
Okay, blood cleansing initiated.
筛检病毒 细菌
Viral and bacterial screening activated.
注射蛋白质 脂肪…
Releasing proteins, fats,
矿物质 碳水化合物
minerals and carbs.
能量注入1320千卡
Energy inflow is at 1320 kilocalories.
开始抗发炎类固醇 贺尔蒙…
Now starting anti-inflammatory corticoids, hormones
及抗生素程序
and antibiotic protocols.
标准每日摄取量
Standard daily intake.
注射抗忧郁剂
Release antidepressants.
给他一个好梦
Let's give him a nice dream.
这些是你配备的武器
All right, here's what you're dealin' with.
改良式M2自动步枪
Modified M2 battle rifle.
点50口径30发
.50 caliber Beowulf ammunition at 30 round clips.
3连发或全自动
Three-shot bursts or full auto.
重装备
Heavy-duty.
TSR 66 卡匣式电击枪
TSR 66. Cartridge-driven taser pistol.
每次二十万伏 可制伏或杀死人
Each projectile releases up to 200,000 volts. It can stun, it can kill
这是致命武器
and it's nasty shit.
最新装甲 但不是射不穿
Your armor, state-of-the-art, but not invulnerable.
点50或更大口径就能杀死你
.50 caliber or larger can penetrate and kill.
多中几枪 你猜谁会被资源回收
Multiple hits, and guess who ends up in the recycling bin?
若觉得需要武器或受到威胁
If you sense you need a weapon or are threatened
面罩会自动落下 武器就绪
the visor goes down and the system makes the weapons available.
但记住 这不算武器
But you gotta remember, it's not the weapons that count.
重点还是在操控的人
It's who's handling them.
虽然你不能算是个人
Or, in your case, what.
- 你办得到吗？- 你负责你的工作就好
- You think you can do this? - Oh, just stick to your job.
我的工作？机器人就是我的工作
Just stick to my job? Combat robots are my job, Doc.
我们的机器在世界各地完美运作
Rio, Congo, you name it, I was there. Our machines run perfectly.
我认为把人放进机器是一大退步
You ask me, stickin' organics into the system is a huge step backwards.
我不管你设计得多好
I don't care how well you designed this thing.
若我不核准 它最好开始学中文
Without my sign-off, it better start learnin' Chinese,
因为它哪儿也去不了
'cause it ain't never goin' home.
我也很高兴认识你
It's nice to meet you, too.
来测试吧
Let's do this,
锡人
Tin Man.
(中国 欧姆尼模拟室)
品质控制 EM-208对战锡人
Quality control, EM-208 versus Tin Man.
开始一号场景
Rendering scenario one now.
希望你不介意
Hey, Doc, hope you don't mind.
我习惯边听音乐边工作
I like a little music while I'm workin'.
我是用空壳做的
When a man's an empty kettle
准备测试 好戏要上场啰
All right. All right, let's let the games begin. Let's rock 'n' roll.
开始测试
Commence scenario.
我以为我可以变成人
Just because I'm presumin' That I could be kind of human
只要我有一颗心
If I only had a heart
我会很温柔亲切 而且绝对体贴
I'd be tender, I'd be gentle And awful sentimental
总是想到爱
Regarding love and art
我会和麻雀和丘比特做朋友
I'd be friends with the sparrows and the boy who shoots the arrows
只要我有一颗心
If I only had a heart
指出阳台
Picture me a balcony
上面的声音在变小…
Above a voice sings low...
转弯时迟疑
Laggin' on the corners.
不 那里 你看见吗？
No, there, d'you see that?
看我的机器人 机器人就该这样
What my robot did, that's how you do it.
新产品会害怕
New product's afraid.
慢了2.3秒 太好了
2.3 seconds behind. Great.
别开枪 他有枪
Don't shoot! He has a gun!
放下武器
Drop your gun!
放下武器 让小孩走
Drop the weapon. Let the kid go!
它担心小孩会受伤
Oh, well, it's worried that the kid's gonna get hurt.
- 让小孩走 - 太糟了
- Let the kid go! - Too bad.
结果慢5.6秒 测试失败
Well, there you have it. 5.6 seconds behind. Scenario failure.
这东西送我都不要
I wouldn't buy that for a dollar.
- 再一次 - 你自找的
- Let's do it again. - Your funeral.
搜寻"艾力克斯墨菲"
Detective Alex Murphy.
搜寻结果
Search results.
墨菲警探恢复迅速
"Detective Murphy making a speedy recovery."
艾力克斯墨菲 他是人还是机器？
"Alex Murphy. Man or Machine?"
克莱拉墨菲不愿意发表意见
"Thrust into the spotlight, Clara Murphy won't talk. "
搜寻"安东尼范伦"
Antoine Vallon.
搜寻结果
Search results.
警方无范伦涉案证据
"DPD says Antoine Vallon no longer suspect due to lack of evidence."
搜寻《底特律自由报》
Detroit Free Press.
不幸的是 墨菲一开始
Unfortunately, Murphy's investigation into Antoine Vallon
就擅自调查范伦
wasn't authorized in the first place.
是墨菲警探太过热心
Look, Detective Murphy was simply overzealous, okay?
没有证据显示范伦企图杀他
We have absolutely no evidence linking Vallon to the attempt on his life.
我只想说我的搭档是个好警察
All I'm gonna say is my partner's a great cop.
我一定要抓到想杀他的人
And I won't rest until the men who tried to kill him are brought to justice.
(底特律 欧姆尼总部)
他有什么问题？
What's wrong with him?
没问题
No, nothing, nothing.
你看208的反应
Watch the procedural bars on the 208.
评估威胁 做出反应
The machine assesses the threat and acts.
就这样
That's it.
只需两步骤 但你看艾力克斯
It's two steps. Now watch Alex.
软体评估威胁 和机器一样
The software assesses the threat, just like the robot.
把资讯传到大脑
And it sends the information to the brain.
艾力克斯的大脑接受讯息然后…
Alex's brain receives the information and decides what to do with it
像一般人一样由情绪认知下决定
based on his emotional cognitive abilities like any man would.
大脑再与人工智慧模组相连…
Then the brain relates this to the Al module and...
慢上一整年
Yeah, like, you know, a year later.
由电脑完成工作
And our computers finish the job.
你要把人放进机器
Raymond, you wanted a man inside a machine.
这就是结果
And that's what you've got.
人类元素一定会存在
But the human element will always be present.
人的各种情绪
Fear, instinct, bias, compassion,
都会干扰系统
they will always interfere with the system!
好的 但是 丹尼
Okay, but, Dennett,
我必须给美国人能支持的东西
I've gotta give the American people something they can root for.
能激励人心对吧？
Something aspirational, right?
让人相信的东西
They have to believe in this thing.
"普通好"不够 我不会卖普通
"Pretty good"? I don't know how to sell "Okay".
快上市了 我们一定要成功
We, you and I, have got a release date, and we've gotta make it, okay?
我不管你怎么做 我只求你
So I don't care how you do it. I'm askin' ya, come on, can you help me?
让他变成那样
Just get him to do that. Get him to do that.
那是机器
That is a machine.
我知道 但人在机器里
I know, but it's a man inside a machine.
不对 这就是人在机器里
No, that's a man inside a machine right there!
他的命就靠这个
And his life depends on it.
欧姆尼的未来也靠这个
And the future of Omnicorp depends on it
所以回去中国修好这个问题
so get your ass back to China and get it fixed.
我不管你怎么做 做就对了
I don't care how you do it, just go do it!
有花生酱的味道
It tastes like peanut butter.
我没办法把味道弄掉
I can't get it out of my mouth.
你不喜欢花生酱？
And you don't like peanut butter?
不喜欢
No.
金 你喜欢花生酱吗？
You like peanut butter, Kim?
我喜欢
I love it.
好
Okay.
我现在要让你睡觉 艾力克斯
I'm gonna put you to sleep now, Alex.
好
Okay.
让他睡觉 金
Now, put him under, Kim.
你打算怎么做？
What are you planning to do?
认知不过是…
Consciousness is nothing more
资讯的处理
than the processing of information.
我要操控他的认知
I'm gonna fix him.
但他不会发现
And he won't know the difference.
- 雷蒙？- 什么事？
- Raymond? - Yeah?
我们在监狱做焦点小组测试
We just ran focus groups at Ryan Correctional Facility.
这叫"作战模式"
We call this Combat Mode.
真的能让受刑人害怕
It really put the fear of God into the prisoners.
好 还可以
Yeah, that's okay.
看一下这个
And get a load of this.
- 这是什么？- 改变后小孩子爱死了
- What's that? - He transforms. Kids love it.
- 真的吗？- 焦点小组的反应很好
- Really? - Focus group numbers through the roof.
- 是吗？- 没错
- Really? - Oh, yeah.
真是难看
Well, that's really embarrassing.
这是什么？你知道吗？
What is this? You know what?
人们对那些他们之前
People really don't know what they want
没看过的东西没有概念
until you show it to 'em most of the time.
把他变得更…
Make him more, uh,
更有战斗力
tactical.
让他看起来…
Make him look, uh...
把装甲变黑色
Let's go with black.
对
Yeah.
(中国 欧姆尼测试中心)
艾力克斯
Alex.
他看起来造价昂贵
He looks like a billion dollars.
26亿
2.6 billion.
我是雷蒙赛勒斯
Raymond Sellars.
很高兴终于见到你
I've looked forward to meeting you, Detective.
谢谢你为我做的事
I really appreciate everything you've done for me.
这个计划就是要帮助像你这种人
Well, we funded this program to give men like you a second chance.
尽全力就好
You just do your best today.
- 可以开始了吗？- 开始吧
- Shall we? - Let's.
- 赛勒斯先生 欢迎 - 很好
- Mr. Sellars, we're ready for you. - Okay, great.
首席技术员舒曼
Chief Technician Shuman.
早安
Mornin', folks.
等一下的流程是这样
Okay, so this is how it's gonna be.
我们俩对决 先倒下的人输
We're goin' toe-to-toe. Last man standing wins.
你输的话要重新设计
I hit you, you go back to the drawing board.
赢了就搭飞机回家
You hit me, you get a ticket back home.
我的机器人发射点47的子弹
My guys are gonna be shootin' .47 caliber rounds.
这些子弹不会让你倒下
Do a little damage, but they can't take you out.
不过别搞错 我的枪会让你倒下
But make no mistake, Tin Man, my gun will.
艾力克斯 听我说
Alex, listen to me.
EM-208会试着让梅托斯射你
The EM-208s will try to maneuver you so Mattox can get a clear shot.
别被射中
Do not let that happen.
要是梅托斯射中你 否则系统会关机
If Mattox hits you, everything but your life support will shut down.
你会感受到不曾经历过的疼痛
You'll feel more pain than you've ever felt in your life.
是吗？我想我经历过不少
I don't know about that. I've been through a lot.
好
All right.
数到三开始
I say we go on three.
三
Three.
那边感觉如何？
How's it going down there?
无论如何 不要被射到脸
Whatever you do, don't get shot in the face.
哇
Wow.
(剩38个威胁)
(剩37个威胁)
(剩36个威胁)
(EM-208瞄准)
诺顿博士 他怎么做到的？
Dr. Norton, how is he doing this?
他的软体更快 硬体更强
His software is faster. His hardware is stronger.
他是更好的机器
He's a better machine.
但你说人会迟疑
But you said humans hesitate.
只有在下决定
Only when they're making decisions.
不是他在下决定？
He's not making decisions?
是也不是
Yes and no.
在日常生活 人类的规则凌驾于机器
In his everyday life, man rules over the machine.
由艾力克斯决定
Alex makes his own decisions.
但一交战时
Now, when he engages in battle,
软体就取得主控权
the visor comes down and the software takes over.
然后机器负责所有事
Then the machine does everything.
艾力克斯只是过客 就像乘客
Alex is a passenger, just along for the ride.
但是机器负责时
But if the machine is in control,
主导墨菲什么？
then how is Murphy accountable?
是谁扣下板机？
Who's pulling the trigger?
一旦交战时
Well, when the machine fights,
系统释放信号到艾力克斯的大脑
the system releases signals into Alex's brain
让他以为他在做电脑做的事
making him think he's doing what our computers are actually doing.
我是说 艾力克斯以为是他在控制
I mean, Alex believes right now he is in control.
其实不是 只是自由意志的幻觉
But he's not. It's the illusion of free will.
可恶
Crap!
(剩2个威胁)
你让机器以为它是人
So you've circumvented the law by creating a machine that thinks it's a man.
这样违法
But that's illegal.
不对
No. No, no, no.
机器以为它是艾力克斯墨菲
It's a machine that thinks it's Alex Murphy.
在我看来
And in my book
这是合法的
that's legal.
做得好
Well done.
很好
博士 混球被电击会怎样？
Hey, Doctor, what happens if I tase an exoskeleton with a little asshole inside?
我们也很想知道
I, uh, I think we're all curious to find out.
动手吧
Go ahead.
(剩1个威胁)
(剩0个威胁)
要是我有脉搏一定跳很快
If I had a pulse, it'd be racing.
她等了四个月
She's been waiting four months.
我相信她也很紧张
I'm sure hers is, too.
不会有事的
You're gonna do fine.
(欢迎爹地回家)
我喜欢你的海报
I love your sign, D.
嘿
Hey.
没什么好紧张的
There's nothin' to be nervous about.
谢谢你 丹尼
Thank you, Dennett.
我的荣幸
It's been a privilege.
爸
Hi, Dad.
你知道我很想你
You know I missed you, buddy.
我也是
Me, too.
你要摸摸看吗？
Wanna feel it?
那是什么？
What is it?
没关系 宝贝
It's okay, sweetie.
我有录下红翼队的所有比赛
I saved all the Red Wings games on my computer.
是吗？
You did?
- 他们表现如何？- 我不知道
- How'd they do? - I don't know.
我在等你跟我一起看
I've been waiting to watch them with you.
你知道我很想
You know I'd love to, kiddo.
但今晚不行
But I can't tonight.
因为我的装备需要一些…
You know, 'cause Daddy's suit needs some...
特殊处理
Some special handling.
你了解吗？
Do you understand?
(欧姆尼企业)
(警察专用出入口)
谢谢你来 杰克
Thanks for coming, Jack.
听说你回家
I heard you went home already.
克莱拉一定很高兴
I know Clara must be thrilled to have you back.
我看到克莱拉和大卫
I saw Clara and David.
那已经不是我家
That ain't my home right now.
我家现在是该死的实验室
It's in a damn lab across the hall.
我很遗憾 艾力克斯
I'm sorry, Alex.
我明天就要去逮范伦那帮人
Startin' tomorrow, I'm gonna take down Vallon and his whole damn crew.
我正希望听你这么说
I was waitin' to hear you say that.
至少你现在肤色对了
Least I know you're the right color now.
派特 今天这里的低温
Pat, the cooler temperatures here today
完全没有浇熄民众的热情
certainly have not stopped people from showing up.
我们期望底特律市每个角落的市民
We're expecting people from every corner of the city
纷纷走上街头以行动表示他们
here in Detroit to come out and show their support
对艾力克斯墨菲的支持
for Detective Alex Murphy.
很多人对他的外表感到好奇
You know, a lot of questions on people's minds today is what will he look like.
他会变成另一个人吗？
Is he a changed man?
消息指出他现在就在警局大楼
Rumor has it he is in the building preparing to come out...
艾力克斯 现在上传整个底特律警局资料库
Alex, we're gonna upload the entire DPD database into your brain.
也就是说你能立即取得犯罪纪录
That means you'll have instantaneous access to criminal records
还有2011年到现在的监视器影像
plus an archive of CCTV footage from 2011 to the present.
好的
All right.
来吧
Hit me.
金 交给你了
Okay. Kim, it's all yours.
监视器影像上传成功
Archive footage uploading successfully.
你的系统会自动连线
Your system draws connections automatically.
这会连接肇事者的犯罪记录
It will link perpetrators to their crimes
和他们的具体位置传送给你
and give you their exact locations whenever available.
我有证据可以逮捕138名…不
I got evidence to make 138... No, no.
166名罪犯
166 arrests.
他的情绪稳定
His emotions are stable.
不可思议
This is incredible.
他的家人现在也在警局里
You will notice his family is here in the building as well.
市长现在已经上台
The mayor is standing onstage behind me.
还有欧姆尼企业的雷蒙赛勒斯
Also, Raymond Sellars from Omnicorp.
他们看来交情很好
They seem like great friends
显然他们合作愉快
obviously echoing the partnership that they've brought together.
还需要多久？
How much longer will this take?
资料库快上传好了
Well, the feed from the database is almost done, so.
我们现在要上传最近的资料
We're approaching present day.
634名罪犯待捕
634 pending arrests.
我们需要更大的监狱
We're gonna need a bigger prison.
他压在她身上
He's on top of her.
诺顿博士 他太激动了
Dr. Norton, he's getting too emotional.
- 我得阻止他 - 艾力克斯
- I gotta do something! - Alex.
艾力克斯 冷静
Alex, calm down.
深呼吸
Take a breath.
放轻松
Relax.
金 读数怎么样？
Kim, what are the readings?
我没见过这么高的读数
I haven't seen him at levels like this.
- 他要开枪射他们 - 艾力克斯
- He's gonna shoot 'em! - Alex!
艾力克斯 放轻松
Alex, Alex, relax.
放轻松
Relax.
艾力克斯？
Alex?
- 怎么回事？- 电脑故障吗？
- What is this? - This just a computer glitch?
不 这是他受害当天的影像
No. That's his own crime scene.
艾力克斯
Alex!
他太激动了
He's spiking all over the place.
艾力克斯
Alex!
- 艾力克斯 - 系统会当机 博士
- Alex? - The system is crashing, Doctor.
艾力克斯 听得见吗？
Alex, can you hear me?
艾力克斯
Alex! Alex!
- 我不确定他能不能承受 - 我一定要马上处理
- I'm not sure he can handle this. - I gotta do something!
他情绪高涨
He's emotionally overloaded.
放开我
Unlock me!
艾力克斯 停止
Alex! Stop!
停止 他痉挛发作
Stop! He's having a seizure!
金 快关机 艾力克斯
Kim, shut him down! Alex!
我要和博士讲话
Get me a live feed!
不行 博士和病人一起
I can't do it. Dr. Norton's with the patient.
现在就要
Do it now!
老天
Jesus Christ!
诺顿博士
Dr. Norton! Dr. Norton!
- 什么？- 媒体在等
- What? - The press is waiting!
他该出去了
We have to get him up there now!
你没看见他变这样？
What do you want me to do?
修好他 该怎么做就做
I don't know! Fix him! Do what you have to do!
这攸关你和我们的名声
Your reputation is on the line every bit as much as ours.
没时间了
We're running out of time.
好吧
Okay.
所有人都出去
Everybody out!
出去
Out!
市长即将介绍
Mayor Durant is about to take to the stage
底特律打击犯罪的最新武器
and introduce Detroit's newest weapon in the war on crime.
市长现在要开始致词
I'm actually getting word that he's ready to go right now.
心跳加速 他又开始激动
Heart rate rising. He might start spiking, Doctor.
清除多巴胺和正肾上腺素
Set modules to absorb dopamine and noradrenalin.
但他的情绪会消失
But you'll be taking away his emotions.
照我说的做
Drop the levels until I tell you to stop.
他会没办法感受任何事
Doctor, you'll be taking away his ability to feel anything.
现在就做
Now, please!
重复播放他遇害的影像
Pull the footage. Put it on a loop.
多巴胺浓度20%
Dopamine level's at 20%.
再降低
More.
多巴胺10%
Dopamine level's at 10%.
再低
More.
- 多巴胺5% - 再低
- Dopamine level's at 5%. - Lower.
- 他已经没感觉了 - 再低
- You're flattening him out. - Lower!
- 2% - 维持这样
- 2%. - Hold it there.
艾力克斯？
Alex?
艾力克斯 你感觉如何？
Alex, how do you feel?
很好 诺顿博士
I feel fine, Dr. Norton.
今天我要谈的不是犯罪预防
Well, today I'm not here to talk about crime prevention.
而是解决方案
I am here to give you the cure.
好耶
That's right!
爸
Hi, Dad!
爸？
Dad?
(无威胁)
改革从现在开始
Ladies and gentlemen, the revolution begins right now
欢迎艾力克斯墨菲警探
with Detective Alex Murphy!
警探
Detective.
(无威胁)
- 他在干嘛？- 他活像个僵尸
- What's he doing? - He looks like a zombie.
他正在搜寻犯罪资料
I think he's accessing criminal data.
(无威胁)
(威胁)
(谋杀通缉犯)
汤玛士金 你被捕了
Thomas King! You are under arrest!
(诺维克关键时刻)
(底特律警局总部)
今天以前 汤玛士金这个罪犯
Until today, Thomas King was a convicted felon
犯下强暴 纵火及谋杀罪行
wanted for rape, arson, and murder.
这个人造成许多美国家庭破碎
This man has torn apart American families.
他在逃六年
On the loose for six years.
这个狡猾的罪犯躲在哪里？
And where was this criminal mastermind hiding?
就在警察局总部前面
Right in front of the police headquarters.
他离警察只有几步
Here he is, just steps away from two of Detroit's finest.
这两名警察完全不知道
These two officers are completely unaware
坏人就在人群之中
of the monster in their midst.
然后 在60秒内
And then, in 60 seconds...
我重复 只花了60秒
I repeat, just 60 seconds,
墨菲警探就把他绳之以法
Detective Murphy brings him down.
要是你无力负担我们会指派律师
If you cannot afford an attorney, one will be provided for you.
各位 这就是美国正义的未来
This, my friends, is the future of American justice.
多少个汤玛士金要为他们的罪行
How many like Thomas King will pay for their crimes
付出代价？
now that RoboCop is here?
是的
Yes,
我们不要逃避这个话题
let's not shy away from what this means, people.
人无法胜任这项工作
Men weren't up to the task.
但是艾力克斯墨菲…
But Alex Murphy,
一个机器战警…
a robot cop,
能胜任
was.
我们不能把他收起来
We can't take him off the street.
这就是我所说的 他大受欢迎
This is what I'm saying. He's a hit.
他是当红炸子鸡
A big, fat, stinking hit.
对啊 等他在街上崩溃就完了
Yeah, until he breaks down in front of everyone.
我们都知道可能会有问题
Hey, we all knew there would be issues. It's inevitable.
丹尼 我相信你能解决这个问题
Dennett, you're my guy. I just need you to get a handle on this.
但我需要时间
I know, but I need more time.
这状况没人碰过
Scientifically, we're in uncharted water.
他必须回实验室做更多测试
We need to take him back to the lab and do more tests.
好像有东西在干扰我们的系统
I mean, it was like something was interfering with our system.
化学或物理之外的东西
Something beyond chemistry or physics.
像什么？他的灵魂？
Like what? His soul?
听着 现在不能临时喊卡
Hey, look, this train has already left the station.
我不能出去向外界说
I can't exactly go out to the world and say,
抱歉产品有瑕疵
"Sorry, I released a defective product."
所以不论如何 他必须待在街上
So, no matter what we do, we just need to keep him on the streets.
媒体访问呢？
What about the interviews?
取消 全部取消
Cancel 'em. Cancel all of 'em.
取消所有宣传
Everything.
事实上 丹尼…
In fact, Dennett.
也让他家人保持距离
Let's keep the wife at a distance for now, as well.
我想见他
I'd like to see him.
你可以帮我安排吗？
Can you arrange that?
我不想骗你
Look, I won't lie to you.
艾力克斯很紧张 我们必须镇静他
Alex was so nervous, we had to sedate him.
我看着他眼睛 我看不见我老公
I looked in his eyes and I couldn't see my husband.
他在儿子面前开枪 这不是镇静
And then he just shoots a man in front of our son. That's not sedation.
他现在对药物的反应不一样
He's responding to drugs differently now.
我们从一开始就知道
We both knew from day one,
可能有副作用
there would be complications.
再给我一点时间
Just give me a little more time.
我保证
I promise,
你老公会回来
you'll have your husband back.
各部门的各小队都一样
This goes for every squad in every department.
墨菲警探可以插手所有调查
Detective Murphy will have full access to all investigations.
抢劫 毒品 凶杀案
Robberies, narcotics, homicides.
要是他要求接手 案子就归他管
If he requests to take over a case, the case will be handed to him.
没有异议 不准抱怨
No arguments, no complaints.
太扯了
This is bullshit!
我说不准抱怨 我是认真的
I said no complaints! And I mean it. Now...
早安 局长 各位警官
Good morning, Chief Dean. Good morning, officers.
我今天选了13个谋杀通缉犯
I've selected 13 targets for today, all wanted for murder.
约翰毕格斯是第一个
John Biggs is target number one.
我会接手这个案子
I'll be taking over this case.
救护车 警车 验尸官
Ambulances, detention vehicles, and coroners
全部待命 我随时召唤
should be ready to move in on my request.
祝各位今天愉快
I wish you all a very good day.
墨菲
Murphy.
你还好吗？
You okay, man?
我很好 警官
I'm fine, Sergeant.
等不及要去抓坏人
Can't wait to get back to work.
雷克和丹尼尔一定紧张死了
Lake and Daniels are in there shittin' their pants...
抱歉 我有案子要办
Excuse me, I have casework.
(主要目标 约翰毕格斯)
(取得监视器影像)
(搜寻)
(未发现目标)
(已知关系人)
(搜寻)
(发现目标)
(目标华特凯洛已定位)
(模拟处理)
(确认3个威胁)
不要开枪
Don't shoot! Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
华特凯洛 看着我
Walter Karrel, look at me.
你有两个选择
You have two options.
第一
Option one.
我用五万伏特电击你
I shoot you with 50,000 volts
可能造成呼吸衰竭 器官失常
which may cause respiratory failure, organ malfunction,
内部灼烧 大小便失禁
internal burns, and loss of bowel and bladder control.
然后我逮捕你
And then I arrest you.
第二 你告诉我约翰毕格斯在哪
Option two. You tell me where John Biggs' drug lab is located.
然后我逮捕你
And then I arrest you.
你有两秒钟决定
You have two seconds to decide.
完全合法
Totally justifiable.
我们要发大财了
We are going to make a lot of money.
没有恐惧 没有心跳加速
Nothing. No fear. No increase in heart rate.
没有一丝愤怒或任何情绪
No traces of anger whatsoever.
恭喜 博士
Congratulations, Doctor.
你做到了
You did it.
对 我做到了
Yes, I did.
我早就说
I told you, sir.
诺顿根本无法控制这个产品
Norton clearly never had control of the product.
我同意 所以我把你找来
I agree. And that's why I called you here.
我要你盯着这个计划
I just want a second pair of eyes on this thing, that's all.
好
Okay.
我要取得锡人视像
I'll need a feed from the Tin Man's head
监视整个实验室 以及…
plus full surveillance of the lab, and...
你能取得所有东西
You're gonna have full access to everything.
若要找我 我会在华盛顿
If anything comes up, I'm gonna be in Washington.
(诺维克关键时刻)
他带来和平
He brought peace
即使在美国最暴力的城市
to this country's most violent city.
他让所有人看到
He showed us all
底特律和美国有更美好的未来
that Detroit and America can have a brighter future.
今晚我们邀请有远见 爱国的…
On tonight's show, a visionary and true patriot.
欧姆尼企业执行长赛勒斯先生
The CEO of Omnicorp, Raymond Sellars.
(关键面对面)
- 你好 派特 - 雷蒙
- Hello, Pat. - Raymond.
谢谢你邀请我来
Thanks for havin' me.
你现在一定开始庆祝了
You must be doing a victory lap about now.
这个嘛
Well.
两周前 欧姆尼的股价一飞冲天
Two weeks ago, Omni's stock went through the roof.
以及参议院最终同意
And the Senate has finally agreed
表决废除崔佛斯法案
to vote on the repeal of the Dreyfus Act.
舆论终于转向
Well, look, I mean, the tide is definitely turning.
我想机器战警很快就能捍卫美国
I just feel certain that soon we'll be keeping all Americans safe.
我也这么希望
I certainly hope so.
但下一位来宾有不同的观点
But, I think our next guest will have a different point of view.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
修伯崔佛斯
Hubert Dreyfus.
参议员 谢谢你上节目
Senator, thank you for joining us.
派特你好 赛勒斯先生
Hello, Pat. Mr. Sellars.
参议员 你知道这是什么吗？
Senator, do you know what this is?
美国民众对崔佛斯法案的意见分歧
The American public is divided on the Dreyfus Act.
我们网站上的民调结果平手
Our polls at Novakelement.com are tight at 50-50.
毫无疑问 欧姆尼企业引起关注
There is no doubt Omnicorp created a sensation
但这法案不是关于艾力克斯墨菲
but this bill is not about Alex Murphy.
而是要不要让机器人掌握
It's about whether America's willing to give robots
人类的生杀大权
the authority over human lives.
不 听我说
No. Look, look, look.
我们观察到的舆论转向 让我们知道
This sea change we're witnessing, and it is a sea change,
美国人不在意
shows that Americans don't really care
执法人员是不是人
if our law enforcement systems are manned or unmanned.
他们关心的是效率和安全
What they care about is efficiency and they care about safety.
你在模糊焦点
You're clouding the issue.
你们推出墨菲就是为了改变舆论
This is clearly an attempt to sway public opinion with a marketing stunt.
很明显的是
What's clear is
一个机器人就让犯罪率降低80%
that with just one system in place, we've cut crime by 80%.
想像如果有100个机器人
Just imagine if we put, I dunno, let's say 100 systems in place.
我想知道你为什么要反对？
And then, I want you to ask yourself, why are you holding us back?
- 这是你的计划？- 谢谢你 参议员
- Is that your plan? - Thank you, Senator.
- 谢谢你 雷蒙 - 谢谢 派特
- And thank you, Raymond. - Thank you, Pat.
你们都听到了
Well, there you have it.
谁会反对降低犯罪？
Who could argue with that?
难道说…
Which begs the question.
美国参议院支持犯罪？
Has the US Senate become pro-crime?
嗨
Yeah, hi.
不 五千
No, no, 5000.
明天打给我
Call me tomorrow.
嘿 范伦在等你们
Hey, guys. Vallon's waitin' for you inside.
你不陪我们进去？
What, you too busy to walk us in?
我在努力工作
I'm out here makin' money.
我要的陷阱呢？难道要我自己做
Where are my trip wires? I gotta do this myself?
- 你们怎么这么慢？- 怎么堆满这些东西？
- What took you so long? - What the hell is all this shit?
那家伙在街上我没办法卖货
I can't move any product with this thing on the streets.
你们根本没给我保护
What are you doing to protect me?
放轻松 那家伙是僵尸
Relax. The guy's a walkin' zombie.
你们的电话关机了吧
And tell me your phones are off.
他不会来抓你 我们行踪很隐密
He's not going after you. We covered our tracks.
他不能捏造证据
He can't manufacture evidence outta thin air.
就算他来 我也不怕他
If he does, I'm ready for him.
什么事？
Well?
我接到电话
I've been getting calls.
谁的电话？
From whom?
克莱拉
Well, Clara.
你必须让她见她丈夫 她有权利
You need to let her see her husband. She has rights.
不是你说了算 这由法律决定
That's not your decision. That's Legal's call.
对 但她迟早会向媒体爆料
Yeah, but it's only a question of time before she turns up on television.
她可以试
Well, she can try.
我会对她下封口令才让她见
I'll issue a gag order before I let her see her husband.
真是个好主意
I'd hop to it.
艾力克斯
Alex. Alex!
艾力克斯 你必须回家一趟
Alex. You need to come home.
克莱拉 请让开
Clara, please stand aside.
你必须和大卫谈谈
You need to speak to your son.
现在有三起犯罪进行中
Right now, I see three crimes in progress.
艾力克斯 听我说
Alex, listen to me.
我知道你在里面
I know you're in there.
(情绪分析 焦虑)
大卫不肯去上学
David won't show his face at school.
他晚上做恶梦
He's having nightmares.
他快撑不住 我也快撑不住
He's falling apart. I am falling apart.
拜托
Please.
我自己办不到
I can't do this on my own.
你出事那晚他吓坏了
He's been scared ever since that night.
(机器不会做爱)
(人需要工作 机器不需要)
你觉得她会怎么做？
What do you think she's gonna do?
他会怎么做？
What's he gonna do?
(取得监视器资料库)
(格兰赫斯特小学影像)
(大卫墨菲情绪评估)
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
大卫
David? David.
退后 请退后
Stand back. Come on, stand back!
(情绪低落)
他应该要看这个
He's supposed to be watching this.
但他选择看大卫到学校的影像
Instead, he's accessing images of Clara and David arriving at school.
重复看好几次
Over and over again.
他覆写系统的优先权
Somehow, he's overriding the system's priorities.
- 你要我把他关掉吗？- 不
- Do you want me to shut him down? - No.
还不要
Not yet.
我想看会发生什么事
I wanna see what happens.
(扫描犯罪现场)
(艾力克斯墨菲谋杀案)
他到他家干嘛？
What's he doing at his house?
看吧 他没遵守程序
Look, he's disobeying protocol.
你该把他关掉
You have to shut him down.
我觉得他还是在做他的工作
As far as I can tell, he's still doing his job.
(侦测4支摄影机)
(处理1号摄影机资料)
(处理2号摄影机资料)
(处理3号摄影机资料)
(处理4号摄影机资料)
(模拟环境)
(目击证人 克莱拉墨非)
(情绪评估 极度焦虑害怕)
(生理状况)
(生命垂危)
给我他脑的影像
Adrian, give me an image of his brain.
他解除我们对他的设定
He's undoing what we did to him.
他的多巴胺回到正常浓度
His dopamine levels are coming back to normal.
这怎么可能？
How is that even possible?
我也不知道
I haven't the faintest idea.
艾力克斯
Alex.
(目击证人 大卫墨菲)
(情绪评估)
(高度震惊害怕)
艾力克斯 拜托你回局里
Alex, please return to the station.
我要做一些测试
I wanna run some tests.
这下好玩了
Well, this should be interesting.
(重设优先权 取得犯罪资料库)
(艾力克斯墨菲谋杀案)
(主要嫌犯 安东尼范伦)
(监视器现场影像)
(搜寻…)
(未发现目标)
(已知关系人)
(搜寻…)
(未发现目标)
你电话拿来
And your phone on the table!
我们不是警察 我们替范伦工作
We're not cops, all right? We work for Antoine Vallon.
- 哇哦 - 你说什么？
- Whoa! - What'd you say?
我们替安东尼范伦工作
We work for Antoine Vallon.
(主要目标 杰瑞怀特)
(搜寻…)
(发现目标)
(目标已定位)
我的手
My hand, man!
安东尼范伦在哪里？
Where's Antoine Vallon?
你弄断我的手
You broke my hand, man!
我知道你记得我 杰瑞
I know you remember me, Jerry.
范伦在哪里？
Where's Vallon?
等下
Wait a minute.
我告诉你他会杀掉我老婆和小孩
If I tell you where Vallon is, he'll kill my wife and kid, man.
(取得市民纪录)
(无子女 已离婚)
你老婆2019年告你家暴诉请离婚
Your wife left you in 2019 after filing charges for domestic abuse.
你没有小孩
And you don't have a kid.
不过我有
But I do.
我不会问第二次
I'm not askin' again!
我发誓 我不知道他在哪
Look, I swear, man. I don't know where Vallon is, okay?
我只和他司机马可仕联络 真的
The only guy I talk to is his driver Marcus. That's it, man. That's it!
他有电话吗？
Does he have a phone number?
(取得行动电话资料库)
(身份 马可仕普莱斯)
(信号已定位)
(所在位置类型 仓库)
有麻烦了 艾力克斯不遵守程序
We have a problem. Alex is breaking protocol.
他在干嘛？
What's he doing?
他在侦办他自己的谋杀案
He's off solving his own murder.
真是天才
Oh, that is genius.
我怎么没想到？
Why didn't I think Of that?
他多久会到？
How long till he gets here?
- 五分钟 - 好
- Five minutes. - All right.
强尼 你看着监视器
Johnny, you stay on these monitors.
怎么回事？
What happened?
有白痴用未加密电话
Some idiot used an unencrypted phone.
可恶
Shit.
(信号已定位)
(失去信号)
你们听好
All right, everyone, listen up!
他来了
He's coming.
不干掉他 你们就死定了
He leaves alive, you don't.
要怎么杀他？
How do we stop him?
用点50以上的子弹 瞄准头部
.50 caliber and above. Aim for the head.
设定好了
This one's set.
走吧
Let's go. Go!
好 走吧
All right, move! Let's go!
快点
Come on. Come on!
可以了
Ready to go!
炸弹装好了
They're all set.
(消除0个威胁)
(启动热影像)
(消除11个威胁)
(消除12个威胁)
(消除17个威胁)
(消除18个威胁)
(消除19个威胁)
(消除20个威胁)
杀了他
Finish it!
(消除30个威胁)
去死吧 怪胎
You freak, die!
(主要目标 安东尼范伦)
(生理状况)
(死亡)
(扫描指纹)
(提取指纹)
(搜寻指纹资料库)
(识别中)
(完成)
小心
Watch out.
要找医生吗？
Need me to call a doctor?
跟我来 杰克 你会喜欢的
Come on, Jack. You're gonna like this.
干什么？
What the hell you doin' here?
你想玩好警察配坏警察？
Y'all gonna play good cop, bad cop?
不对 是坏警察配机器战警
Nah, Daniels. Bad cop, RoboCop.
我在范伦仓库找到26把枪
I've recovered 26 guns from Vallon's warehouse.
13把符合证物室失踪的编号
Thirteen serial numbers match weapons missing from Evidence.
上面布满你们的指纹
And I got your prints all over 'em.
你胡说
This is bullshit.
我有你们和范伦密那天企图谋杀我的影像
I also have CCTV footage of you and Vallon the same day he tried to kill me.
那就收买他 有什么问题？
So put him on the payroll. Why we talkin' about this?
他不会收 现在他搭档又受伤
It won't work. Now that his partner got hit, he's never gonna let it go.
- 这是什么？- 路易斯住的医院
- What is that? - Lewis' hospital.
墨菲下午会去探病
Murphy's dropping by this afternoon.
杀警察要躲一辈子…
I kill a cop, I'm lookin' over my shoulder...
你知道警察在牢里的下场吗？
You know what they do to cops in prison, man?
和被你们抓的人关一起？
Being locked up with the same dudes you put in there?
(威胁 暴力即将发生)
你觉得他会不会出卖你？
How long you think before he gives you up?
不要杀我 拜托
Don't shoot me. Okay?
我发誓 是局长
I swear to Christ. It was Dean.
是她偷枪出去 不要杀我
She helped pull those guns. Just don't shoot me.
谢谢你的合作
Thank you for your cooperation.
你可以上手铐了 杰克
You can cuff him now, Jack.
(嫌犯 凯伦狄恩)
(搜寻 拨出电话)
(找到 加密电话)
现在我知道为何抓不到坏人
Now I know why we couldn't get an arrest.
因为范伦受到你的保护
'Cause Vallon was protected from up on high.
艾力克斯 我可以解释
Alex, I can explain.
你今天给他警告
You tipped him off today.
喂 伙计 别这样
Come on, man. Don't do this.
你已经试着杀我两次
You tried to kill me twice.
我信任你 你却毁掉我的家庭
I trusted you. And you destroyed my family.
认罪
Confess.
(高度害怕)
现在 在所有人面前
Now, in front of everyone.
认罪
Confess!
怎么了？
What happened?
我让锡人倒下 没办法
Tin Man is down. Had to be done.
为什么？
Why?
产品射杀贪污警官
Product shot a corrupt cop.
再慢个两秒 早间新闻
Two more seconds, the chief's brains
头条就是局长被杀
would've been splattered across the 6:00 news.
她真的有罪？
We got anything on her?
她是底特律警局局长
Well, she's the Chief of the Detroit Police Department.
你说呢？
What do you think?
你知道吗？
You know what?
这可能刚好助我们一臂之力
This might actually tip this thing right into the net.
艾力克斯 我不知道你是否听见
Alex, I don't know if you can hear me.
但今晚 你直捣歹徒的巢穴
But tonight, you uncovered a nest of vipers
就在底特律警察局里
inside the Detroit Police Department.
你让我们看见无价的真相
And in so doing, you shed light on an invaluable truth.
那就是即使是警察
Even the police,
誓言保护民众安全的人民褓姆
the men and women who swore to keep us safe,
也可能被收买
they can be bribed.
也可能被贿赂
They can be bought.
然而 机器不会被贿赂
Machines, however, are corruption free.
美国人可以活在一个…
Americans could be living in a country
执法有效率而且没有贪腐…
where law enforcement is not only efficient,
的国家
but incorruptible.
谢谢你 艾力克斯 你的所为
Thank you, Alex, for all you've done.
谢谢你做的一切
And for all that you are.
墨菲警探现在状况危急
Detective Murphy is currently in critical condition.
我们的医生正在全力抢救
Our doctors are working ceaselessly
但目前情况还不明朗
but, at this time, it is unclear if he will survive.
克莱因女士 你认为警察涉嫌谋杀墨菲警探
Ms. Kline, how do you think the attempt on Detective Alex Murphy's life
是否影响明天的崔佛斯法表决？
will affect tomorrow's vote for the Dreyfus Act?
与此同时 我们现在只关心
At this time, Omnicorp's sole concern
墨菲警探的伤势复原情况
is the full recovery of Detective Murphy.
墨菲警探要为他的国家捐躯几次才算够呢？
How many times does Detective Murphy have to give his life for his country?
希望参议院能投下正确的一票
I sincerely hope the Senate makes the right vote tomorrow
不要让艾力克斯墨菲白白牺牲
so that Alex Murphy's sacrifices will not have been in vain.
崔佛斯参议员是我的朋友
Senator Dreyfus is my friend.
他是我的导师 是我的支柱
He has been my mentor and my strength
在困难时给我支持
in times of difficulty on this floor.
尽管如此 我服务的是俄亥俄州
But despite all that, I work for the state of Ohio,
选民的安全是我的优先考量
and the safety of its citizens is my top priority.
所以我投赞成
So I vote yes.
崔佛斯法案必须被否决
The Dreyfus Act must be repealed.
我们以39比10领先
That's us ahead, 39 to 10.
参议院联络人说我们会获胜
I spoke to the Senate liaison and it looks like it's in the bag,
但和政治人物合作还是要小心
but we still have to tread carefully with the politicians.
记者在底特律警局现场连线
We're here live at DPD headquarters
刚刚克莱拉墨菲发表声明
where moments ago, Clara Murphy made a shocking statement.
搞什么？
What the hell?
欧姆尼不让我们探望艾力克斯
Omnicorp has denied me and my son access to Alex for weeks.
我要求知道真相
I demand to know why.
这种处置不人道 有人必须负责
This treatment is inhuman and somebody needs to be held accountable.
我们完蛋了
Oh, we're fucked.
只要再12票
No, we only need 12 votes.
她不会影响投票
She shouldn't make much difference.
对 但投票过后呢？
Yeah, but what about after the vote?
他们不该见面
I mean, those two should not be allowed contact.
要是她影响他…
If she starts putting ideas in his head...
带她过来 我来跟她谈…
Bring her in. I'll handle the explanation.
艾力克斯呢？
And what about Alex?
不幸的是 不能一直冰冻他
You know, unfortunately, we can't just keep him on ice.
他在警局开枪吓到一些政治人物
The shooting at the station spooked some of the politicians.
我们必须安抚这些客户
They're our clients. We have to take care of them.
客户乐见机器降低犯罪率
They're fine when a machine is lowering the murder rate,
但不希望有人调查贪腐
but when a man is investigating city politics, they get nervous.
首先 他不是人 好吗？
All right. First off, it's not a man, okay?
它是欧姆尼企业的财产
It's property of Omnicorp.
再说你根本不用担心政治
And politics are the least of your concern.
这东西破了自己的谋杀案
I mean, this thing solved its own murder.
难道不会发现我们操控他？
How long till it realizes you haven't been on the level with it?
要是这样
If that happens,
要是这样记者会争相采访他
every journalist in this country is dying to speak to him.
我们创造出一个英雄
I mean, we created a hero.
若他揭发我们就糟了
What happens when he opens his mouth?
什么比英雄更伟大？
What's bigger than a hero?
死掉的英雄
Dead hero.
叫诺顿过来
Get me Dr. Norton.
你搞什么 雷蒙？
What is this, Raymond?
你派梅托斯监视我 又骗说他有生命危险？
You have Mattox spying on me and now this bullshit about a "critical condition"?
我们都知道艾力克斯没事
You know and I know Alex is fine!
冷静
Calm down.
丹尼
Dennett.
你的研究太伟大 我不…
Your work is so good, I don't...
这跟我的研究无关
Well, now, this is not about my work!
你看见那女人上电视
You saw the woman on TV!
这场闹剧必须停止
This has to stop!
你是对的
You're right.
但我问你一件事 丹尼
But let me ask you something, Dennett.
我们给艾力克斯墨菲什么样的生活？
What kind of life have we really given Alex Murphy?
他永远没办法活得像正常人
He's never gonna be a normal man, a father, a husband.
等其他机器人上街 他就…
By the time we put the other units on the street, he's just...
丹尼…
Dennett.
我们承认吧
Let's face it.
我们失败了
We failed him.
我们辜负艾力克斯墨菲
We failed Alex Murphy.
但我要你顾全大局
But I want you to think about the bigger picture
这才是重点
because that's what we're talking about.
你的工作会被研究数十年
The work you've done with him is gonna be studied for decades.
你改变历史 丹尼
You've changed the face of history, Dennett.
不再有警察因为执行勤务死亡
No policeman is ever going to die in the line of duty again
全都是因为你
because of you.
你考虑看看
You think about that.
我要他的家人受到妥善照顾
I want that family taken care of
超过他们的想像
beyond their wildest dreams.
- 我们欠他们的 - 我同意
- We owe them that. - I agree.
我要十年的全额资金赞助
I want full funding. Ten years.
新职员 我要自己挑人
New staff, all my own people.
没问题
Fantastic.
成交
Deal.
怎么回事？
Hey. What's going on?
警卫来了 他们要所有人出去
Security's here. They're clearing everyone out.
他们不让他醒来
They're not waking him up.
不论你做什么 别丢他一个人
Whatever you do, don't leave him alone.
什么叫不让他醒来？
What do you mean they're not waking him up?
(艾力克斯墨菲状况稳定)
投票结束
The voting period has ended.
结果已经出来
The clerks have tabulated the results.
赞成63票
The yeas are 63.
反对22票
The nays are 22.
大部分参议员都投票赞成
A majority of senators have voted in the affirmative.
崔佛斯法案正式被否决
The Dreyfus Act has been repealed by Congress.
你们动作真慢
God, you guys are slow, like a bunch of girls.
我是梅托斯
This is Mattox.
丹尼同意了
Bennett's on board.
也该是时候了
It's about time.
下令吧
Call it.
把事情办好
Get it done.
乐意之至
My pleasure.
- 墨菲女士 - 你可以来我家
- Mrs. Murphy... - You can come here as much as you want.
你可以威胁我告我 拿走我的房子
You can threaten me. You can sue me. You can take my home.
但我不会罢手 你懂吗？
But I am not gonna stop till I see my husband. Do you understand that?
赛勒斯先生想见你
Mr. Sellars would very much like to see you.
艾力克斯还好吗？
Is Alex okay?
他有重要讯息告知 你要来吗？
He has important information to share with you. Will you accompany me?
大卫
David.
我们要出门 去拿外套
We gotta go. Can you grab your coat?
嘿
Hey!
我正要坐电梯下去
I'm in the elevator, on my way down.
我要进实验室
I need access to the lab.
不行 他们还在这里
That's insane. They're still here.
你去引开他们
Distract them.
好
Okay.
我不能…
I cannot...
这里有个女的歇斯底里
There's a lady in here going hysterical.
她把门锁上不让我们进去
She will not let us in. She's got the codes for the door.
我重复 她不让我们进去
I repeat, she will not let us in.
小姐 你必须让我们进去
Lady, you need to let us in there now. We have to get in there.
你听不懂我说的话吗？
Are you not understanding what I'm saying?
要是有人死掉你要负责吗？
Do you wanna be responsible for the deaths of everyone in this building?
站住
Hey! Stop!
别开枪
Don't shoot!
出来
Step outside.
解除传输器
Unlock the transmitter!
传输器解除
Transmitter unlocked!
(艾力克斯墨菲 传输终止)
(无生命迹象)
请墨菲女士进来
Send in Mrs. Murphy, please.
是 先生
Right away, sir.
叫醒他
Wake him up!
艾力克斯
Alex! Alex!
艾力克斯 我是诺顿博士 快醒来
Alex, it's Dr. Norton, you have to wake up!
艾力克斯 听得见吗？
Alex, can you hear me?
这些人要来杀我们
These men are here to kill us.
他们要来杀我们
They're here to kill us, for chrissakes!
墨菲女士 昨天晚上…
Mrs. Murphy, last night,
艾力克斯的精神崩溃
Alex had a psychotic break.
他杀了一名同事 然后痉挛发作
He killed an unarmed colleague and later suffered a seizure.
我们尽力了
We did everything,
我们已经尽全力还是救不了他
everything, we could, but the doctors couldn't save him.
我很抱歉 墨菲女士
Very sorry, Mrs. Murphy.
我们很快就会发布消息
We're going to be making the announcement shortly.
你把我关掉 她差点就认罪
You shut me down. I was about to get a confession.
是梅托斯关掉你
Mattox shut you down.
传输器拔掉就不会再发生
I've removed your transmitter so he won't do it again.
赛勒斯不想让你醒来
Sellars can't afford to wake you up.
他派这些人来拔插头
He sent these guys to pull the plug.
他要你死 艾力克斯 你了解吗？
He wants you dead, Alex. Do you understand?
有什么我们能做的请尽管开口
Sorry. If there's anything we can do for you and David, we'll do it.
我不要你的东西
I want nothing from you.
我了解
I understand.
你滚开我们的生活
You stay out of our lives.
你和你的公司都是
You and your company.
如果你希望这样
If that's what you think is best.
还有一件事
There's one more thing.
这对大家都好 尤其是大卫
I think it would be to the benefit of everyone, especially David
就是不要公开这件事
if we kept this matter private.
我们不想破坏艾力克斯的形象
We don't wanna damage Alex's legacy.
艾力克斯
Alex! Alex!
我可以解决这个问题
I can fix this!
你骗我
You lied to me.
你骗我老婆
You lied to my wife.
你替那些想杀我的人工作
You're working for the people that are trying to kill me.
博士 你还要我相信你？
You want me to trust you, Doctor?
艾力克斯 我可以去找媒体
Alex, I can go to the press!
艾力克斯 我可以告诉他们真相
Alex, I can tell them the whole story!
艾力克斯
Alex!
听我说 拜托
Listen to me, please!
艾力克斯
Alex! Alex!
搞什么？
What the hell?
行动照旧
Keep all our systems at green light,
帮我接赛勒斯
and for chrissakes, get Sellars on the phone.
收到
Roger that.
可恶
Damn, damn, damn, damn, damn!
看看这座城市
Look at this city.
多么美丽
So beautiful.
这城市变得多么和平
It's become so peaceful.
我希望…
I wish
我能为底特律带来好消息
I had some good news for Detroit.
但不幸的是
I have very sad news.
尽管我们全力抢救
Despite our best efforts to save him,
艾力克斯墨菲仍在几小时前去世
Alex Murphy passed away just hours ago.
艾力克斯墨菲是…
Alex Murphy was...
赛勒斯先生
Mr. Sellars.
- 什么？- 梅托斯打来
- What is it? - Mattox just called.
请跟我们离开
We need you to come with us now.
女士 请往另一边走
Ma'am, I need you to turn around and go the other way, please.
- 你说什么？- 发生紧急状况
- What are you talking about? - We have a security situation here.
请往另一边走
I need you to turn around and go the other way.
我们要搭外面那台车…
Sir, there's a car outside that's supposed to...
那里封锁了 现在快走
That area is locked down. Now go.
- 发生什么事？- 我说快走
- What's happening? - I said go!
我要和赛勒斯先生说话
I wanna talk to Mr. Sellars.
赛勒斯先生
Mr. Sellars.
- 直升机还要多久？- 大概10分钟
- How close is that helicopter? - About 10 minutes, sir.
(主要目标 雷蒙赛勒斯)
(涉嫌谋杀艾力克斯墨菲)
- 对不起 - 什么事？
- Excuse me. - Yes?
我要找杰克路易斯警官
I need to speak with Sergeant Jack Lewis.
是紧急事件
It's an emergency.
稍待 赛勒斯先生
Stand by. Mr. Sellars.
克莱拉墨菲要求见你
Apparently there's a Clara Murphy in the lobby.
要是她看见他 计划就泡汤了
Raymond, if she sees him, we are dead in the water.
- 你要怎么做？- 带墨菲女士上来
- What do you wanna do? - Bring Mrs. Murphy up here.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
诺顿说他们大楼使用机器人
Norton said they may be using drones for protection.
所以不管做什么 千万别拔枪
So whatever you do, do not draw your weapons.
没拿武器就不会被杀 清楚吗？
They won't shoot if we're unarmed. Clear?
- 清楚 - 清楚
- Clear. - Clear.
站住
Hold it right there.
不要动
Don't move.
(模拟处理)
这是私人产业 你无权进入
This is private property. You are not authorized to be here!
如果我是你们 我会把枪放下
I'd put those guns down now if I were you.
- 放下武器 - 好 我们让开
- Stand down. - All right, man, we're good.
(寻找清楚射击目标)
开下去
Head to the lower level.
停车
Hold up, hold up!
撞开
Ram it!
快点
Gun it.
快
Go. go, go! Now!
(ED-209瞄准)
(目标受阻)
艾力克斯 快跑
Alex, run!
欧姆尼警卫 放下武器
Omnicorp Security! Drop your weapons!
放下武器
Drop your weapon.
举起双手 没有人会受伤
Keep your hands above your head and no one will be harmed.
发生什么事？
What's going on?
墨菲女士 你听清楚
Mrs. Murphy, I want you to listen to me carefully.
艾力克斯的有机部分已经死掉
The organic part of your husband Alex is dead.
但机器部分功能失常
The robotic part of him is malfunctioning,
他在大开杀戒
and he's shooting up the building.
所以我们必须带你们离开
So we've gotta get you and your son out of here right away.
我接个电话
I gotta take this call.
他离开大厅往上走
He just left the lobby and he's headed our way.
收到
Roger that, sir.
- 别开枪 他是我的 - 知道了
- Don't shoot. My robot. You just flank. - Got it.
锡人
Tin Man.
它在这
Oh, there it is.
你看来好惨
You look like crap.
怎么回事？
What's the matter?
不能开枪？
Can't shoot?
嗯？
Huh?
(红色资产 不得攻击)
你在想什么？这不符程序
What were you thinking? This isn't a drill.
你是机器人
You're a robot.
我是红色资产 我自己写的程式
I'm a red asset. Wrote that myself.
怎么样？
What do you think?
来啊 尽管开枪
Come on, Tin Man, just pull the trigger.
快啊
Pull it.
你可以跑
You can run.
快跑
Go on.
跑
Run.
Run!
没错 跑吧
There you go. Run.
快跑
Run. Run!
哇噢
Whoo!
很痛 对吗？
Stings like a bitch, don't it?
算你幸运 枪没设定在致命模式
Aren't you lucky I didn't have my gun set to "kill"?
听着
Hey, listen.
这不是私人恩怨
This isn't personal.
也许有一点
Well, maybe a little.
不过我要让你解脱
I'm gonna put you out of your misery.
直升机来了
Helicopter's approaching.
赛勒斯先生先上
Mr. Sellars boards first.
不 墨菲女士你们先上
No, no, no. Mrs. Murphy, you and your son can get on first.
警官受伤
Officer down.
欧姆尼大楼的…
Mechanical room.
机械室
Omnicorp Building.
收到 救援马上到
Roger that. EMS on the way.
你不会有事 杰克
You're gonna be okay, Jack.
没有生命危险
It's nonfatal.
快去
Go. Go.
直升机即将降落
Omni-LZ Helo-1 on approach to deck.
那是什么？
What's that?
- 他有枪 - 什么？
- He's got a gun! - What?
快离开
Pull up! Pull up!
- 他搞什么？- 抱歉 我不知道
- What the hell is he doing? - Sorry, sir. I don't know.
艾力克斯？
Alex?
爸？
Dad?
克莱拉 大卫
Clara, David.
哇噢 哇噢
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
等一下
Wait.
- 你们走开 - 艾力克斯 把枪放下
- Get out of the way. - Alex, put down the gun.
克莱拉 带大卫离开这里
Clara, take David and get out of the way now!
雷蒙赛勒斯 我要逮捕你
Raymond Sellars, you're under arrest
罪名是你企图谋杀警察
for the attempted murder of a police officer.
你要逮捕我？好
Are you here to cuff me? All right.
来啊 来抓我
Go 'head, cuff me.
不行 程式不是那样设定
You can't. You're not programmed that way.
要是你违背程式 系统会当掉
If you go against the program, the entire system shuts down, so.
你没拘捕令 我们可以不追究…
You don't even have a warrant. We'll overlook this little...
趴在地上 手放背后
Get down on the ground and put your hands behind your back.
我只负责行销
I'm just from marketing.
- 现在 - 好
- Now! - Okay, yep, yep, yep. Yep.
艾力克斯 我们必须合作
Alex, we need to work together here.
有我的技术你才能活着
Because I'm the only one with the technology to keep you alive.
不管死活 我都要逮捕你
Dead or alive, you're coming with me.
好
All right.
给我枪
Weapon.
艾力克斯 老实说 我不想伤害你
Alex, honestly, I mean you no harm.
若我要你死你早就死了
If I wanted to, I could have killed you a long time ago.
只要轰掉你的脑袋
I just aim this right at your head and blow it off.
赛勒斯 拜托 不要
Sellars, please! Don't!
若我高兴 我也可以瞄准你家人
I mean, if I wanted to, I could just aim this at your little family
我可以干掉他们
and I could just kill them too.
而你根本无能为力 因为现实是…
And really, there's nothing you could do about it because, let's face it,
你是机器人
you're a robot.
你了解吗？
Do you understand that?
艾力克斯
Alex.
爸
Dad!
宝贝
Baby.
嘿
Hey.
不会有事的
Everything's gonna be all right.
你觉得如何？艾力克斯
How you feeling, Alex?
我准备好了
I'm ready.
他准备好了
He's ready.
(诺维克关键时刻)
目前欧姆尼的母公司 尚未做出任何回应
There's still no word from Omnicorp parent company, OCP.
政府表示正在重建艾力克斯墨菲
And although the government says they are rebuilding Alex Murphy,
但情况还是众说纷纭
rumors continue to swirl about his condition.
不过我们取得独家手机拍摄画面
But we have obtained exclusive video taken by cell phone
显示艾力克斯墨菲可能很快…
that shows the people of Detroit may have Alex Murphy back on the streets
就会回来
sooner than they think.
不过不幸的是
The real tragedy here
总统决定维持崔佛斯法案
is that our president chose to uphold the Dreyfus Act.
(机器人遭否决 总统引述诺顿证词)
我认为他受到偏颇的媒体…
Now, I have no doubt he was manipulated by our biased media
和告密者丹尼诺顿的影响
and by whistle-blower Dennett Norton.
我们知道的比想像中的少
I acknowledge we know less than we thought.
我相信我的研究计划没有错
But I do believe my research program is sound.
但我应用它的方式
What I did with it
错了
was wrong.
这个天杀的混蛋
The fact that this mother...
没被关进联邦监狱
is not serving time in some federal penitentiary
根本就是天大的错误
is a huge, hot, heaping pile of horse...
有些观众可能认为这样想太危险
Now I know some of you may think that this kind of thinking is dangerous
认为这些机器违反公民自由
and these machines violate your civil liberties.
有人甚至觉得在海外使用机器
Some of you even believe that the use of these drones overseas
让我们成为侵略别国的美帝
makes us the same kind of bullying imperialists
我们祖先逃离的那种国家
that our forefathers were trying to escape.
对这些人 我要说…
To you, I say...
停止抱怨
Stop whining!
美国现在是…
America is now
而且永远都会是…
and always will be
地球上最伟大的国家
the greatest country on the face of the Earth!
我是派特诺维克
I'm Pat Novak.
晚安
Good night.